Love and imagination can change the world.
Barbie as Rapunzel is a animation, family film directed by Owen Hurley.
Barbie stars as Rapunzel, a young girl who is entrapped by
a magical barrier by the wicked, Gothel.
Rapunzel finds an escape where she finds a Prince and a feud between two
kingdoms which goes back to the day she was kidnapped as a child.
Barbie Roberts / Rapunzel (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Gothel (voice), played by Anjelica Huston.
Penelope (voice), played by Cree Summer.
Hobie / Palace Guard (voice), played by Ian James Corlett.
Stefan (voice), played by Mark Hildreth.
Hugo / General (voice), played by David Kaye.
Barbie as Rapunzel is a 2002 animated fairy tale film co-produced by Mainframe
Entertainment and Mattel Entertainment, and distributed by Artisan Home Entertainment.
An adaptation of the 1812 German fairy tale "Rapunzel" by the Brothers Grimm, it is the second
in the Barbie film series, with Kelly Sheridan providing the voice of Barbie.
Barbie as Rapunzel was released on VHS and DVD on October 1, 2002, later
making a television premiere on Nickelodeon on November 24, 2002.
and was subsequently released overseas through
Entertainment Rights and Universal Pictures Video.
The film was nominated for eight DVD Premiere Awards, winning Best Original
Score and Best Animated Character Performance for Gothel.
The film explores themes of princess, magic, based
on toy, female protagonist, dragon.